<data>
  <event start="Fri Dec 17 2010 00:00:00 GMT-0600" title="Protests Begin in Tunisia">
    In Tunisia, Mohamed Bouazizi, a 26-year-old fruit and vegetable seller, sets himself on fire after police confiscate his cart because he doesn't have a permit; he dies later from his injuries. Protests quickly spread nationwide.
  </event>
  <event start="Tue Jan 14 2011 00:00:00 GMT-0600" title="Tunisian President Toppled">
    After weeks of violent protest, Tunisian President Zine El Abidine Ben Ali flees to Saudi Arabia, ending more than two decades of authoritarian rule.
  </event>
  <event start="Tue Jan 25 2011 00:00:00 GMT-0600" title="Dissent Spreads To Egypt">
    Egyptians begin mass demonstrations, similar to the ones in Tunisia. Protests center on Cairo's Tahrir Square.
  </event>
  <event start="Thu Feb 03 2011 00:00:00 GMT-0600" title="Discontent in Yemen">
    Mass protests begin in Yemen, where President Ali Abdullah Saleh has ruled for more than three decades.
  </event>
  <event start="Fri Feb 11 2011 00:00:00 GMT-0600" title="Mubarak Steps Down">
    Egyptian President Hosni Mubarak resigns after 18 days of protests against his rule and heads to the Red Sea resort of Sharm el-Sheikh.
  </event>
  <event start="Mon Feb 14 2011 00:00:00 GMT-0600" title="Violence In Bahrain">
    Large-scale protests begin in Bahrain. They last for weeks, but a government crackdown and the intervention of troops from nearby Saudi Arabia eventually suppress the demonstrations.
  </event>
  <event start="Tue Feb 15 2011 00:00:00 GMT-0600" title="Unrest In Libya">
    In Libya, protests begin in the eastern city of Benghazi after the arrest of a human-rights activist.
  </event>
  <event start="Sat Mar 05 2011 00:00:00 GMT-0600" title="Libyan Rebels Assert Control">
    After taking control of Benghazi, Libyan rebel leaders declare themselves the country's official representative.
  </event>
  <event start="Wed Mar 16 2011 00:00:00 GMT-0600" title="Syrians Rise Up">
    Protests begin in Syria, where President Bashar Assad, and his father before him, have ruled for four decades. Protests quickly escalate, and the government responds with a harsh crackdown.
  </event>
  <event start="Thu Mar 17 2011 00:00:00 GMT-0600" title="No-Fly Zone For Libya">
    The U.N. Security Council authorizes a no-fly zone over Libya. NATO airstrikes begin two days later.
  </event>
  <event start="Fri Jun 03 2011 00:00:00 GMT-0600" title="Yemeni President Leaves Country">
    After months of protests in Yemen, President Saleh is badly injured in an explosion at the presidential compound in the capital, Sanaa. Saleh goes to Saudi Arabia for extended medical treatment, but refuses to relinquish power.
  </event>
  <event start="Wed Aug 03 2011 00:00:00 GMT-0600" title="Mubarak Goes On Trial">
    Former Egyptian President Mubarak goes on trial, appearing in a Cairo courtroom in a cage for the defendants.
  </event>
  <event start="Sun Aug 21 2011 00:00:00 GMT-0600" title="Libyan Rebels Enter Tripoli">
    Libyan rebels enter the capital, Tripoli; longtime leader Moammar Gadhafi goes into hiding. Sporadic fighting continues for the next two months as the rebels pursue Gadhafi’s dwindling band of loyalists.
  </event>
  <event start="Thu Oct 20 2011 00:00:00 GMT-0600" title="Gadhafi Killed">
    Moammar Gadhafi is killed after being seized by a mob near his home town of Sirte.
  </event>
  <event start="Sun Oct 23 2011 00:00:00 GMT-0600" title="Tunisians Vote">
    Tunisia holds the first elections in an Arab Spring country where an authoritarian ruler was toppled in 2011. The Islamic party Ennahda wins.
  </event>
  <event start="Wed Nov 23 2011 00:00:00 GMT-0600" title="Yemen’s President Resigns">
    Yemen’s President Ali Abdullah Saleh signs an agreement in Saudi Arabia to step down from power after 33 years of rule. However, he returns to Yemen, where his relatives and longtime associates continue to hold power in the deeply divided country.
  </event>
  <event start="Wed Nov 23 2011 00:00:00 GMT-0600" title="Report Finds Abuses In Bahrain">
    In Bahrain, a special commission that examined the government’s response to an uprising says the security forces used excessive force against protesters and tortured detainees. King Hamad bin Isa Al Khalifa promises reforms. But critics say the report and the proposed changes do not go far enough.
  </event>
  <event start="Mon Nov 28 2011 00:00:00 GMT-0600" title="Egyptians Go To The Polls">
    Egyptians begin voting in parliamentary elections that are carried out in phases. The Muslim Brotherhood leads in the early stages of the voting.
  </event>
  <event start="Mon Dec 12 2011 00:00:00 GMT-0600" title="Syrian Dead Estimated At 5,000">
    The U.N. estimates that 5,000 Syrians, many of them unarmed civilians, have been killed in nine months of violence.
  </event>
</data>